# **Shyam Patel**

## Data Engineer | ML Engineer

★ Gujarat, India | \( \subseteq +91 \) 7778858278 | \( \subseteq \subset

nttps://github.com/ShyamPatel1320 | mhttps://medium.com/@shyampatel1320 | 🛕 https://shyampatel1320.github.io/portfolio/

# **Summary**

With over 1.5 years of combined experience as a Data Engineer and Machine Learning Engineer, I have actively contributed to various projects, including multiple data engineering and machine learning projects. I also write blogs on topics related to data science. My expertise lies in Snowflake database migration, AWS technologies, SQL query writing, Machine Learning Algorithms, and Python programming, with a track record of successful project implementations.

## **Experience**

#### Ridgeant Technologies **Q**Ahmedabad

#### Data Engineer – (Dec-2022 – Present)

- Spearheaded a key role in the Finance Project and Home Rental Analysis project, collaborating with the data
  engineering team to successfully migrate data from one platform to another using cutting-edge tools like AWS,
  Oracle, Snowflake, and Informatica Cloud.
- Played a pivotal role in optimizing data workflows and enhancing data quality, ensuring seamless data migration, and processing.

#### MEDIUM Blogger- (Sept-2023 - Present)

- Passionately create and publish insightful, beginner-friendly blogs on Medium.com, aimed at demystifying complex data science concepts for a wider audience.
- Utilize relatable real-life examples to simplify intricate data science topics, attracting an expanding readership and receiving positive feedback from the data science community.

#### Prompt Softech - Software Development Company ♥Ahmedabad:

#### Data Scientist (Intern) - (May 2022 - July 2022)

- Collaborated with a team of data scientists to develop an innovative image-based deep learning model for automatically extracting temperature panel digits from milk container images.
- Conducted image annotations, participated in model building part.

#### **Skills**

**Programming Languages**: Python, C++, SQL, Core Java

Tools and Technologies: Snowflake, SQL Server, Access DB, AWS lambda, AWS GLUE, AWS SES, DBT, Machine Learning Algorithms, Computer Vision, Deep Learning Concepts, Sk-learn, Data Structure and Algorithms, NLP, Generative AI

Soft Skills: Quick Learner, Creativity, Problem Solving

## **Education**

Degree	Course	Institute	CGPA
Bachelor of Engineering	Computer Engineering	LDRP Institute of Technology and Research	8.43

## **Achievements and Certifications**

**NPTEL Certification:** Successfully completed the NPTEL Exam with a consolidated score of 72% in <a href="Python for DataScience">Python for DataScience</a> **Coursera Certification:** successfully completed the 6 Course Program by Google, which is <a href="Google IT Automation with">Google IT Automation with</a> Python.

**DBT Fundamentals** - I have completed the <u>DBT Fundamentals</u> course and received my badge for completion. **In addition**, I have participated in various hackathons and completed multiple courses on platforms such as Coursera, Great Learning, and Udemy. I also actively solve problems on platforms like HackerRank, LeetCode, and GeeksforGeeks.